<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Euz blog</title><link>https://blog.euz.me/</link><description>Recent content on Euz blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.euz.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>30 Days Of Maldev In Delphi - Part 1</title><link>https://blog.euz.me/p/30-days-of-maldev-in-delphi-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euz.me/p/30-days-of-maldev-in-delphi-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/fr/a/a1/Delphi-logo-1024.png" alt="Featured image of post 30 Days Of Maldev In Delphi - Part 1 " />&lt;h2 id="tldr">TL;DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve felt the urge to learn a new language and chose Delphi after a chat with bro DarkCoderSC.&lt;br>
I created a &amp;ldquo;30 days&amp;rdquo; program bootcamp style using ChatGPT 4o because Laluka convinced me of the power of LLMs during a training I took with thim.&lt;br>
I&amp;rsquo;ll be randomly pushing updates as part of blog posts (not one per day, rather packed ones).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="delphi-in-2025-wtf-bro-">Delphi? In 2025? WTF Bro ?!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.euz.me/images/memes/deckard.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Meme : Stay awhile and listen"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I was chatting with DarkCoderSC about the last snippet he published on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.malwaregallery.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Malware Gallery&lt;/a> that reminded me of good old Sub7 times.&lt;br>
And I must confess, I texted him &amp;ldquo;Bro, seriously, Delphi in 2025? Is it still any good for maldev nowadays?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a quick chat he convinced me that people still have a bad opinion about Delphi because they got stuck on what Delphi 7 looked like. He even made me want to believe that Delphi will be cool again pretty soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I keep chasing new projects and quickly get bored if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t spark joy, so I saw an opportunity there to do two things I had planned to do for a long time :&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Learn a new language&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Get back to MalDev stuff&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The problem was that I don&amp;rsquo;t know shit about Delphi, didn&amp;rsquo;t know where to start, what to do etc.&lt;br>
So I decided to head to ChatGPT and have a chat with &lt;del>Skynet&lt;/del> it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why ChatGPT? I&amp;rsquo;m not much into the AI/LLM hype, but when I took a training at &lt;a class="link" href="https://offenskill.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Offenskill&lt;/a> with Laluka, he got me hyped about how efficient ChatGPT could be for small, highly scoped tasks when you know how to ask.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did my best to make it create something cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It gave me a syllabus that looked nice. So I asked it to build a Github repo with all the information, and break every &amp;ldquo;day task&amp;rdquo; into a specific folder with a dedicated readme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Guess what? It worked until day 4.&lt;br>
The first 3 days were perfectly built, but it had been lazy for the last 27 😂.&lt;br>
I politely asked to finish the job and it did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I created the public &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/Euzebius/30-domid" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>30-domid repo on Github&lt;/a>.&lt;br>
Want to take the challenge too?&lt;br>
Clone and push 😇&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cool-story-bro">Cool story bro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ChatGPT built a program for me and I created a repo, now what you may ask?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I plan to release my progress as blog posts, and source code in a dedicated branch.&lt;br>
Do not expect one blog post per day of program, this will not happen.&lt;br>
Do not expect one blog post per calendar day either, this is unlikely to happen too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what I will do is publishing posts with multiple program days at once. Short enough to prevent brain from melting, but long enough not to think &amp;ldquo;cool, 30 seconds read, genius&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won&amp;rsquo;t also treat this as an actual 30 calendar days program, but rather split it as one &amp;ldquo;day&amp;rdquo; is one task on its own and it should be achieved in less than a man-day of working on it, but I can do multiple days on the same calendar day or make the program day span over multiple calendar days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No commitment either on doing this daily for 30 days. But I will do it until reaching the end.&lt;br>
I know, it might sound like a loser but remember, my place == my rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if you want an insight, I already completed day 1 yesterday quite easily. Yes, I know, installing Delphi 12 CE and creating a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; console app makes me an absolute rockstar thank you! 😂&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.euz.me/images/memes/so-it-begins.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Meme : So it begins"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Euz and this blog</title><link>https://blog.euz.me/about-euz-and-this-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euz.me/about-euz-and-this-blog/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="whoami">whoami&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One more random dude on the Internet.&lt;br>
I love hacking stuff, sometimes I break them, sometimes I fix them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the field for nearly 2 decades now.&lt;br>
I&amp;rsquo;ve also been hosting the French Hack The Box meetup for nearly 4 years now : &lt;a class="link" href="https://htb-meetup-france.super.site/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>see site here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-a-blog">Why a blog?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Why not?&lt;br>
I mean, I was born in the 80s, grew up in the 90s, so the good old Internet. Having a blog in the 90s was cool, I had multiple ones. One per hobby (including gamedev).&lt;br>
But why now? Well, I need to motivate myself to keep doing stuff, and this is a way for me to stay commited. Don&amp;rsquo;t want to get (r|d)usty.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-will-be-presented-here">What will be presented here?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Everything that sparks in my mind and I consider worth sharing.&lt;br>
Might be related to labs, hacking, hobbies, anything.&lt;br>
Don&amp;rsquo;t have too high expectation though.&lt;br>
Sometimes it will be cool, sometimes it will be dull.&lt;br>
Sorry not sorry, my place == my rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resume">Resume&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>TODO&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome message and manifesto</title><link>https://blog.euz.me/p/welcome-message-and-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euz.me/p/welcome-message-and-manifesto/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.euz.me/p/welcome-message-and-manifesto/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Welcome message and manifesto" />&lt;h1 id="welcome">Welcome&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Welcome to this blog!&lt;br>
Why a blog in 2025 you might be asking?&lt;br>
Mate, I&amp;rsquo;m asking the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out I sometimes have random thoughts or things I like to share, and sometimes X or LinkedIn might not be the best place to do this.&lt;br>
I also don&amp;rsquo;t like the fact that in a clap of hands my work could disappear if it&amp;rsquo;s hosted on a social media platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here am I!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.euz.me/images/memes/shithwga.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Meme : Shit, here we go again"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="manifesto">Manifesto&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What can you expect to find here?&lt;br>
Well, mostly random thoughts on things and tech stuff.&lt;br>
I&amp;rsquo;m interested in a lot of topics, so this be anything related to hacking or infosec.&lt;br>
Sometimes other topics maybe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But keep one thing in mind.&lt;br>
I&amp;rsquo;m not the best on any topic.&lt;br>
I&amp;rsquo;m just here to share things with people.&lt;br>
There might be mistakes in what I publish, feel free to reach out and I&amp;rsquo;ll happily correct the mistake and quote you as a contibutor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There will always be someone smarter, faster or stronger.&lt;br>
I just want to share stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won&amp;rsquo;t talk about politics or religion here.&lt;br>
There are places for personal beliefs and they don&amp;rsquo;t include tech blogs imo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Will I publish often?&lt;br>
I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I&amp;rsquo;d rather not publish anything than just throw useless stuff in here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll try to organize posts as much as possible with categories and tags, but I&amp;rsquo;m sometimes messy so please forgive times when I&amp;rsquo;ll just throw stuff and not put them in the appropriate box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fell here randomly and you don&amp;rsquo;t personally know me? Well, feel free to get to know me with the appropriate page 😇&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://blog.euz.me/archives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euz.me/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Links</title><link>https://blog.euz.me/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euz.me/links/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here you will find a list of projects, people or organizations I appreciate.&lt;br>
There is no specific order, I&amp;rsquo;m just adding them here.&lt;br>
In case I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention you and you think this is a mistake, you know where to reach me out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://blog.euz.me/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.euz.me/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>